You can leave me alone just now.
其实你刚才不用管我的
As the captain,
我是队长
it's my duty to protect my members,
有责任维护我的队员
especially on this matter.
尤其是这件事情上
Well, can you open the window?
那你能把窗户打开吗
What's up?
又怎么了
You smell like
你身上有股
smelly salted fish.
臭咸鱼的味道
If I'm not mistaken,
如果我没记错的话
your registration card
你的户籍卡上
says you're fisherman.
写的是渔民
Why aren't you used to it?
怎么会闻不惯呢
I do go to sea for fish,
我是出海打渔
but not for salted fish.
但我不打咸鱼
Move!
走
Hurry.
走快点儿
Hurry up.
快点儿
Don't dawdle.
到门口了还磨叽
You return the car back.
你把车还回去
This is your police ID card.
还有 你的警员证
Take it.
拿着
Captain,
陈队长
may I ask you a question?
能问你个问题吗
Say it.
说
Have you considered the consequence
刚才从货车上被甩下去
of being thrown down from the van?
你有考虑过后果吗
I'm always lucky,
我这人运气一直都很好
or I can't be a policeman.
不然早当不了警察了
Miss Luo,
骆警官
what's wrong with your arm?
你胳膊咋了
Is it injured?
受伤了
Nothing. No worries.
一点儿小伤 不碍事儿
As a cop,
干咱这行啊
it's normal to get minor injuries.
磕磕碰碰在所难免
You will get used to it.
以后这大场面有的是
Erbai, have a pancake here.
二白哥 快过来吃饼
Cool.
好
Miss Luo,
骆警官
did you learn how to arrest people
你在女警训练班
at the training class?
是学过怎么抓人吗
Of course.
那当然了
I didn't learn other courses very well,
我虽然其他学得不太好
but got full marks in martial arts gymnastics.
但是武技体操我是满分
Great.
行啊
Awesome.
厉害
Luo Minmin.
骆珉敏
You caught a thief
第一次出警
in the first mission.
就抓着个小偷
Good job.
值得表扬
Really?
真的
That's enough.
行了 行了
Stop applauding.
你俩别鼓掌了
Listen up.
我还没说你俩呢
Have
你们
a sit.
坐 坐 坐
Can you not be startled so easily
以后咱行动
in the following missions.
能不能别一惊一乍的
You've got a wrong guy.
都抓错人了
We're too nervous.
今天紧张了
So excited.
激动了
I tell you,
我跟你们说
before the mission,
行动之前
you must observe at first, then judge,
你先得观察 再判断
and finally take action.
最后才能行动
Understand?
明白了吗
Got it.
明白
Yuansheng.
向警官
Hello.
有葱油饼一起吃点儿
C'mon.
对对对
No, thanks.
不用了 谢谢
I'm gonna interrogate the prisoner.
我先进去审犯人
Wait.
等会儿
Prisoner?
审什么犯人呢
How much do you know
诱拐案怎么回事儿
about this case?
知道吗
When we looked into it,
我们查这案子的时候
you were not here.
四所还没你呢
It's not your turn
审犯人
to interrogate the prisoner.
轮谁也轮不着你啊
I'm talking to you.
我跟你说话呢
Do you understand?
你听见了吗
Erbai.
二白哥 二白哥
Calm down.
别别别 别生气
Take it easy.
别生气
Enjoy the pancake.
吃饼吃饼
It's getting cold.
饼凉了
Erbai...
哥
I'm going to the bathroom.
上厕所
He's crazy at earning honor.
想立功想疯了
Captain,
陈队长
I wanna participate in interrogation.
我要参与审讯
Why?
为什么呀
Don't forget,
你别忘了
you're just intern.
你还是实习警员
I caught that guy in person.
人是我亲手抓的
Fine, help me do the record.
好 你帮我做笔录
[4 girls in total,]
一共 四个女孩儿
2 in Fenghuang Dance Hall,
两个在凤凰舞厅
and the other 2 in the Great World.
两个在大世界
What are their names?
都叫什么名字啊
How can I remember that?
这我哪儿记得呀
I just need to search for girls.
我只管给舞厅带人
Good look is enough.
长得好看就行
Name is not important.
管她们叫什么名字呢
Don't giggle with me.
你别跟我嬉皮笑脸的
I really don't know
我是真不知道
their names.
她们叫什么
But the places I mentioned
不过那个地方给你们
are absolutely right.
绝对是没错的
They
你们过去啊
must be there.
准能找到人
Sir.
陈队长
I...
我
If you bring
要是这四个女孩儿
these girls back,
全都找回来了
could you get me out of the jail earlier?
能不能少关我几天
Wait.
等一下
there's another case.
还有一个案子
What?
我 这
Another one?
哪还有什么案子
I'm only
我不就
involved in...
就这一个案子吗
Last Wednesday,
上个星期的星期三
have you been to Van Hwa Hotel?
你是不是去过文华饭店
Yes, I have.
我去过
And your staff
那天你们四所的人
have followed to
不是也都追到
the Hotel, haven't you?
文华饭店来了吗
I saw you that day.
其实那天我见过你
At the gateway.
不过是在酒店门口
I also saw
我还看见
you climbing from the exterior wall
你从酒店的外墙
to the window
翻到了三一一房间的
of the Room 311,
窗户外面
pausing for seconds and back away.
停了几秒又退了回去
I...
我 我那天
have been there that day.
确实是去过文华饭店
But I didn't climb on the wall.
但是我没有爬墙
You must have made a mistake.
你肯定是看错人了
You may wanna flip over
我想你是从外墙
from the wall to the fire exit
翻到消防通道
to escape from there.
从那里逃走
But why did you pause
可是你为什么
outside the window
在三一一房间的
of Room 311
窗户外面
for seconds and back away?
停了几秒又退了回去
No, I didn't.
我都说了我没有
You're talking nonsense.
你这 这瞎说
Family Meng
三一一房间
were murdered in Room 311.
是孟家遇害的地方
Have you seen the scene
你是不是从窗户外面
and the murderer
看到了凶案现场
from the window?
还看到了凶手长相
I...
我
Sir.
陈队长
I just cheated several girls,
我就是骗了几个女孩子
and may be put into jail for months.
顶多就关几个月
Don't drag me into something else
你们可千万别把我
and put me in the wrong.
扯到别的事情上来害我
Do you think we may
你觉得我们警察
do wrong to you?
会冤枉你吗
I'll leave you with some time.
给你一点时间想想
Get out.
你出来
Why do you care
你为什么打听
about the murder?
孟家凶杀案
I've been to Van Hwa Hotel that day,
那天我去过文华饭店
and you recorded my statement.
你还给我做过笔录
He is a witness,
他是目击证人
and I'm a policeman now.
我现在又是警察
I may obtain
说不定能问出
some clues from him.
什么线索呢
Why don't you tell me
这么重要的线索
such
为什么你
important information
刚来四所的时候
at the time you came here?
不第一时间向我汇报
I don't trust you.
因为我不信任你
I'm a policeman.
我是警察 你不信任我
Before the killer is caught,
在抓到凶手之前
anyone who went to the Hotel that day
那天去过文华饭店的
is under suspicion.
都有嫌疑
You too.
那你也有嫌疑
Captain,
陈队长
I just need an honour.
我就是想立功而已
Xiang Yuansheng.
向远生
You'd better tell me
你最好把你知道的
everything you know.
全部告诉我
You ready?
想好了吗
I promise that I can
我可以向你保证
keep anything
你说的
from your mouth confidential.
我都可以帮你保密
Proactively providing
主动提供线索
information to assist the police
帮助警察查案
can help alleviate punishment.
可以减轻处罚
Will the punishment
我说了
be less if I...
真的能少关
Then you must
那得看你说的
tell the truth.
是真的假的
Sure.
行
As you ran after me closely that day,
那天你追我追得紧
I had no choice
我没办法
but climbed
我 我只能爬到那个
onto the wall.
饭店的外墙
I wanna
我本来想
look for an empty room
找个没人的房间
to hide in.
就躲起来
But as soon as I reached
结果我刚爬到
the window of the Room 311,
这三一一的窗户外
I saw 3 people lying on the floor,
就看到地上躺着三个人
obviously dead.
一看就死了
They're throat killed.
全都被抹了脖子
The murderer
凶手
seems like a policeman.
好 好像是个警察
A policeman?
凶手是警察
Yeah,
对
just like you.
就 就和你们一样
He's wearing the uniform
穿着警服
and a police cap.
他 他还戴着个警帽
He had a knife in his hand.
手里拿着把小刀
He's rummaging around in the room
我看他好像在翻箱倒柜
for something.
找什么东西
Do you remember
你还记得
his looks?
凶手的大概长相吗
Well...
我想想啊
Paint it down.
画下来
I can try.
我试试
[All out!]
四所的都给我出来
Captain!
队长
Mr. Feng is coming.
冯科长来了
Hi, Mr. Feng.
冯科长
Is this the man
这个人就是
you brought from the French Concession?
你们从法租界带回来的
Yes, sir.
是
We'll take him away.
移交分局了
Go get in.
带走
Yes, sir.
是
Why?
为什么呀
You
你自己心里
don't know why?
不知道为什么
Because you offended foreigners,
因为四所被告到总局了
then were reported to the head office.
惹到外国人了
You may lose your job.
你们警服都穿不了几天
Is it that inspector
是那个督察员
who complained to you?
向您告的状吗
Is that important?
是谁重要吗
Where the prisoner
犯人会被带到
will be taken?
什么地方去
Who is talking to me?
谁在跟我说话
I am.
我
Who are you?
你谁呀
New policeman here.
四所新警员
Xiang Yuansheng
向远生
Is he recruited by you?
这是你招的新人
By the back door.
走后门进来的
I can't manage him.
我也管不着
Wanna know it?
想知道
Listen,
我告诉你
because of you,
就因为你们
I now have to work overtime
我现在要加班加点
to send him to the Municipal Council
把人送到公董局
and have to give an apology.
还得给人赔礼道歉
If the Council cancels the complaint,
那如果公董局撤销投诉
will you bring him
你是不是得把犯人
back to us?
给我们送回来
Wait.
放心
Your punishment will be brought back right away.
处分马上给你们送回来
Let's go.
走
Why are you so aggressive?
向远生你那么冲干吗呀
You get us in trouble again!
你这不又给咱添麻烦吗
Erbai!
二白
I'm going to cook.
我做饭去了
Captain.
队长
[He left after making trouble.]
惹完事他拍拍屁股走了
[Let's leave]
咱也别杵着了
[and go home.]
各回各家
Erbai.
哥
Are those words true?
刚才说那是真的假的
Cross the bridge when you come to it.
船到桥头自然直
The punishment hasn't come yet.
这处分不还没下来呢吗
Go home for dinner.
走 回家吃饭
See you.
走了
[Miss Luo, goodbye.]
骆警官 那我们先走了
[Come in.]
进
Captain.
队长
[What's up?]
怎么了
Well,
是这样的
we might
之后 我们也可能
not be cops after.
当不了警察了
You don't need to
今天的经费
give us the budget for today.
你就不用给我们了
I'll figure it out
我自己会想办法
myself.
去解决的
What budget?
什么经费啊
For the mission.
就是任务经费
Xiang Yuansheng told me
向警官告诉我
it is dedicated to
那是专门
the implementation of the mission.
用作执行任务的
Today, when we shadowed,
今天我们盯梢的时候
we ordered a cup of coffee
正好点了一杯咖啡
and a piece of cake.
和一个蛋糕
Is this enough?
这些应该够了吧
Is there
是不是
no mission budget?
根本就没有任务经费
Are you worried
你是不是担心
about losing your job?
在四所当不了警察
Relax.
你放心吧
I'll write you
如果真的当不了
a letter of recommendation
我会写一封推荐信
for easy job hunting.
让你去别的所的
Thank you.
谢谢队长
No problem.
去吧
Captain.
队长
Did Xiang Yuansheng
向警官
really make a mistake today?
今天真的做错了吗
If I were him,
如果换作是我
I don't know
我也不知道
what to do.
该怎么做才算好
You know,
骆警官
you're kind.
你很善良
If you wanna
如果你想要
be a good cop,
做一名好警察的话
do what you think is right.
做你认为正确的事情
Go home.
回去吧
[Why am I gonna lose my job?]
为什么不让我当警察了
[Stop yelling and crying,]
别叫了 别喊了
[please.]
我求求你了
Stop it.
别叫了
Luo Minmin,
骆珉敏
you're not
四所又不是
the only one
只有你一个人
who will lose the job!
当不了警察
You do break
耳朵都要被你震碎了
my ears!
骆珉敏
I really wanna be a police officer.
我是真的很想当警察
Do you think
你说老天爷
the God forgets me?
不会把我忘记了
As I said, you're not suitable
我就说了你根本不适合
for this job.
当警察
Nonsense. You doomsayer.
你说的都不对 乌鸦嘴
Are you injured?
你受伤了
How did you get injured like this?
你怎么伤成这样
Stop yelling!
你别喊了
I'll take some medicine for you.
我去给你拿药
Stop making noise!
我耳朵都要被你震聋了
[Gosh!]
笨死了真的是
She cries like a pig.
哭得跟猪一样
Is she sad
她是伤心哪
or sick?
还是不舒服呀
She's just sad.
就是伤心 人没事儿
So much?
有这么伤心呢
I think this will
我估计她得
last for several days.
伤心好多天呢
You don't need to stay here.
你们在这儿守着也没用
Go back to sleep.
快回去睡吧
Do you need help?
不用我们进去看看
No.
不用
Fine.
好
Minmin.
姐
What's up?
怎么了 哥
Nothing.
没事儿
You can go back.
你们先回去吧
[Mr. Feng and I]
我和科长
[will sent him to the Council.]
把人带到公董局
[It's so late.]
都这么晚了
[We can do it.]
要不我们去送
[The order of Mr. Feng.]
科长的命令
Yes, sir.
是
[Why did they arrest you?]
他们为什么抓你
Ah...
那个
[I cheated some girls]
我骗了几个女孩儿
[to dance halls.]
去舞厅
[My heart was in the right place actually.]
其 其实我也是好心啊
I just wanna help them
想给她们找一份
find a profitable job.
挣钱的工作嘛
So is it why Chen Hao arrested you?
陈浩抓你也是因为这个
Yes.
对
Anything else?
还有别的事儿吗
No, nothing.
没 没别的事儿
Have you been to Van Hwa Hotel?
你去过文华饭店
I...
我
Do you know a family of people
有一家人在文华饭店
were murdered there?
被谋杀了你知道吗
I don't know.
我 不 不知道
Never heard about that.
这 这我怎么会知道呢
Really.
真 真不知道
Sir.
长官
Where are we going?
这 这是要去哪儿啊
Sir,
长 长官
aren't we going
不 不是说要
to the Council?
要去公董局的吗
Where are you
你 你们这是
about to take me to?
带我去哪儿啊
Get off.
下车
Wait...
不是 长 长官
I...
我 我
Sir...
长 长官 我 我
[Where...]
这是
[are we going?]
这带我 带我去哪儿啊
[Sir...]
长官 你你你
Where are you about to take me to?
长官你们要带我去哪儿
Sir...
长 长官
Where...
这是
You can't...
这 你 你们这
Officer...
警 警官
I...
我跟你说 我这
Excuse me,
麻烦问一下
how many guests
督察员前面
will the inspector meet?
还有几个客人啊
Next is your turn.
下一个就是你们
OK.
好
Great.
谢谢啊 谢谢
Thanks a lot.
辛苦 辛苦
How unfair!
这叫什么事儿啊
I never thought we need to
来一趟公董局
read their expressions
还得看人眼色
and wait for so long
还得在这儿
in the Council.
被晾着排队
Shame on us!
丢人
I'd rather die than coming here
要不是她告我
if it weren't an accusation.
打死我都不来
Gosh.
瞧你这口气
What a tone!
还打死你
I don't think they wanna meet you.
你当人愿意见你啊
How can you dress so casually
这么重要的场合
in such an important occasion?
你就穿这身啊
What's up?
这身怎么了
It's my new outfit.
出门前我刚换的
You can't be serious.
还怎么了这是
It looks like
这什么呀这是
a piece of diaper.
跟尿布似的
I have nothing to say.
懒得说你
[Hey, it's your turn.]
到你们了
One minute!
马上马上啊
Come here.
来 来
What is it?
你干吗呀
Put it on.
把这个戴上
Remember,
记住了
we're asking for a favor.
咱们是来求人的
Be polite!
别冲动
The most important thing is
记住一个字
to bear.
忍
What do you mean?
不是你干吗呀
Hunger attacks me.
突 突然有点儿饿
I'm gonna have a bite.
我就吃 吃点儿馄饨
Eat this.
吃这个
Ronghua!
老左
[Hurry up.]
还进不进去了
You leave me alone again!
你每次都这样
[Quickly!]
快点儿的
Hello.
你好
Where is "Mr. Shi"?
石先生在哪儿
You can speak Chinese.
你可以说中文
OK.
好
Where is Ms. Shi?
好 石督察员在哪儿
In 2003.
二零零三
[Come in.]
请进
Who let you in here?
谁让你进来了
I don't know.
我不知道
I'm actually
刚刚有人说请进
allowed in.
我就进来了
What are you doing here?
你来干什么
What do you mean by this?
陈警官这是什么意思
I don't understand.
什么什么意思啊
OK, whatever.
好 随便吧
Ms. Shi.
石小姐
Inspector.
督察员
Fine.
好
[I come here today]
我今天过来
[to request you to withdraw]
是想跟你商量
[the accusation]
撤销对
[against the Fourth Station House.]
第四警察所的控告
All the officers there
因为这些事情
are suspended from duty because of this.
四所的警员全部停职了
They're innocent.
他们是无辜的
I'll submit
如果能撤销
to any punishment
我愿意接受
if you can do this.
公董局的处分
You're taking the wrong way.
陈队长你会错意了
We're not directed against you,
公董局不是针对你个人
but your behavior
而是你们目中无法
of taking actions injudicially.
越界抓人的行为
Then let's talk about it.
那我就跟你好好聊聊
In the French Concession,
你们法租界里
there is the biggest opium den
有最大的鸦片烟馆
and the biggest casino.
最大的赌场
Bunches of girls
妓院门口
gather in the front of brothels.
成群结队的姑娘
They don't even hide
她们见到巡捕
when they meet policemen.
甚至都不用躲
Why does the Police Service
为什么你们警务处
allow this happen?
纵容这些扎根
Because you don't love Shanghai.
因为你们不爱这里
You don't care about
这片土地的好与坏
anything here.
跟你们没有任何关系
But my colleagues would rather cross the border
而我的警员宁肯越界了
to arrest the suspect.
也要抓到嫌疑犯
Do you know why?
这是为什么
As soon as you have
但凡你要有
discernment,
一点辨别能力的话
you can absolutely make it clear.
你一定能想得清楚
But I won't
但是我不会
put my discernment
把我的辨别能力
and energy
还有精力
on Chinese policemen
浪费在你们这些
just like you guys.
华界的警察身上
Policemen are halved into two types.
警察只分两种
Those can catch criminals,
一种是抓得到罪犯的
and those can't.
一种是抓不到罪犯的
You belong to
还有第三种
the third type.
就是像你这样
unwelcome here.
不受欢迎的警察
Leave my office now
请赶快离开我的办公室
and
还有
it's useless to bribe me.
我不吃贿赂这一套
Ms. Shi,
石小姐
this is
这个
my lunch food that I haven't finished
是我今天着急来见你
because of your obstruction.
没吃完的午饭
I'm not rich enough to bribe you.
我没那个条件贿赂你
Moreover,
还有
you have no idea
你不懂什么是
what the true policeman is.
真正的警察
Ridiculous.
荒唐
Anything else?
还有什么事
Your captain left just now
你们队长刚才来过了
and I think I've made it clear
我已经明确地告诉他了
that I won't withdraw the accusation.
我不可能撤销控告的
Sorry,
抱歉
I was out of line yesterday.
昨天的确是我越了界
But we still have
但我觉得
some possibilities to negotiate.
我们是有谈判的可能性
The officer with you
听昨天跟你
yesterday said
一起的巡捕说
the Council
公董局也是希望
also want to
能够找到
find the murderer.
孟家案子的凶手
Now I have the clues.
现在我有线索
You might overestimate
你可能高估了
my concern about this case.
我对案子的关心程度
Mr. Meng and I
我和孟先生
just have
只不过是
some public affairs communication.
有公务上的往来
But the Council
但公董局是希望
wanna find the murderer indeed.
能够找到凶手的
Only in this way,
因为只有这样
can you give an explanation
才能给
to the industrialists
像孟先生和孟太太
who pays taxes
这样在法租界
in the French Concession
纳税的实业家
like Mr. Meng.
一个交代
The suspect
昨天我抓到的
I caught
那名嫌疑人
witnessed the scene.
他是凶案的目击者
Now Shiliupu Police Station
现在十六铺分局
has taken him away.
接管了犯人
Only the accusation is withdrawn,
只有撤销对四所的处分
can we investigate the truth
我们才能继续查下去
and find out the murderer.
把凶手找出来
I don't know who you are yet.
还不知道该怎么称呼你
I am
我姓向
Xiang Yuansheng.
向远生
Is your credential accessible?
方便看一下你的证件吗
I don't totally trust Chinese policemen.
我不太信任华界的警察
How can you confirm
你怎么确定
the man is a witness?
那个人是目击者
That day,
案发当天
I met him at Van Hwa Hotel.
我在文华饭店见过他
He acknowledged this.
他也已经承认了
So you lived in the hotel.
所以你住文华饭店
Sorry,
抱歉
but I don't wanna talk
我不想讨论
about my private affairs.
自己的私事儿
I went to there
那天我去现场
because the Central Patrol
是因为有中央巡捕的人
saw you
看见你们
and reported
而且上报了
to our director.
警务处的总监
So this case can't be
所以现在这件事情
decided by myself now.
不是我一个人能说了算
But
不过向先生
I'll try to help you.
我可以帮你试试
Thanks.
谢谢
Inspector Shi,
石督察员
I heard that a Chinese policeman
听说有中国警察
requested you for negotiation
来找你谈判
and you agreed to withdraw the accusation.
你答应撤销投诉了
Not sure. Is the director available now?
正在考虑 总监在吗
Yes, you can get inside.
在 你进去吧
Luna.
露娜
Has the director asked
是总监要求
for the takeover of that suspect
华界十六铺分局
by Shiliupu Police Station?
接管那名犯人的
No.
不是
The Station asked for it.
是对方自己提出的
Thank you.
谢谢
Put it away.
你的领结
Have you convinced her?
督察员说通没有
No.
我没说通
But someone else did.
但有人说通了
Who?
什么意思
[Wonton is ready.]
二两馄饨 麻烦端一下
Help me please.
帮我端一下
You haven't explained to me.
还没说明白呢
Where are you going?
你跑什么呀
Do you need a haircut?
先生剪头吗
How long will it be?
要等多久
[Ten more minutes]
十来分钟
[for this gentleman.]
这位先生就剪好了
I'm in a hurry, maybe next time.
我赶时间 下次吧
Sure.
下次来啊
Here's your coffee.
您的咖啡
Thanks.
谢谢
Are you
跟着我
following me for something emergency?
是有什么要紧的事儿吗
Let's come straight to the question.
那我就开门见山了
You disguised yourself as a policeman,
你跑到四所当警察
broke into the Concession for the murder,
为了凶杀案硬闯法租界
and went to the Council
今天跑到公董局
for negotiation.
找人谈判
I wonder
我昨天就想问你
why you're so interested
你为什么对孟家凶杀案
in the case.
这么感兴趣
Do you know Mr. Meng?
你认识孟家的人
No.
不认识
Have you received a task
那就是有人
to investigate?
派你来调查的
I don't wanna talk
我不喜欢聊
about my private affairs.
自己的私事儿
I don't think it's your personal affairs.
这应该不算私事吧
It's a captain's duty
队长了解队员
to understand his group members.
是他的职责
Your credential
毕竟你证件上
shows your name,
写着向远生
age and job.
二十四岁 渔民
All of this seems to
这和我看到的向警官
contradict you.
不太能对得上号
That's a record of the situation then.
那是登记时候的情况
I changed my job
渔民是我
to be a policeman.
现在警察也是我
The credential doesn't lie.
证件没有错
And people sure change.
但人是会变的
So you've changed.
人是会变的
[Are you a coffee person?]
你很喜欢喝咖啡
Sort of.
还行
Sir,
先生
here's your packed
刚出炉的面包
freshly baked bread,
已经帮你打包好了
and the bill.
另外这是今天的账单
Thank you.
谢谢
Honestly,
不过的确
it's weird to drink coffee with you.
和你一起喝咖啡很奇怪
Since we've been suspended,
既然已经停职
[you're not my captain]
现在就不算
[at present.]
是你的队员了
Please stay away
请不要再打扰
from my private life.
我的私人时间
Sir, here's your bill.
先生 这是您的账单
Has that gentleman
刚刚那位先生
not paid for all yet?
不是已经付过了吗
Just for
他只付了
his own.
他自己的那一杯
So expensive.
这么贵啊
Thank you.
谢谢
You're back!
远生哥哥你回来了
I have
远生哥哥
finished my homework
功课我已经做完了
and milk as well.
牛奶也喝完了
I just bought some
我又买了
fresh bread and milk.
新鲜的面包和牛奶
So much!
买这么多呀
Little girl should drink
小朋友不就应该
more milk to keep your body strong.
多喝牛奶长身体吗
I have told you
我不跟你说了吗
I'm not a little girl.
我不是小孩子
Alright.
好
Who is it?
哪位
[I'm Shi Jun, the inspector]
我是警务处石督察员
[of the Police Service.]
石珺昱
Ms. Shi.
石老师
Duoci,
多慈
what are you doing here?
你怎么在这儿啊
[This is the house]
这是远生哥哥
[Yuansheng rented for me.]
给我租的房子
[Yuansheng,]
远生哥哥
[this is Ms. Shi,]
这就是我之前
my French teacher
给你提到过的
I told you before.
我的法语老师石珺昱
Let's get inside the room.
石老师我们进屋吧
You are following me.
你跟踪我
Yuansheng,
远生哥哥
I know Ms. Shi.
我认识石老师
She is very kind to me.
石老师她不是坏人
Please let her in.
你让她进来吧
Sorry to bother.
打扰了
Mr. Xiang,
向警官
Duoci's parents entrusted to me
多慈父母生前
before their death.
对我有些嘱托
Can I talk to her alone?
我能单独和她说两句吗
As quickly as possible.
尽快
This way.
石老师这边
I was sent to Hong Kong
公董局派我去香港
for business for half a month.
出差半个月
I was informed of your experience
我是回上海的船上
on the boat back to Shanghai.
才知道你父母出事的
I've been
我回来之后
looking for you.
就一直在找你
I never thought I'd meet you here.
没想到在这里才见到你
I didn't get hurt at all.
我一点也没有受伤
Yuansheng saved me.
是远生哥哥救了我
Don't worry.
你不用担心
Have you met him before?
那你以前认识向远生吗
No.
不认识
But someone
好像是有人
asked him to send us something.
托他来给我们送东西
What is it?
什么东西呀
A book.
就是这本书
Someone hid our boat tickets
有人把船票和证件
and credentials inside
藏在书壳里面
and asked him to give it to us.
托远生哥哥带给我们
Is that what he told you?
是向远生告诉你的
In Van Hwa Hotel,
在文华饭店
there's a man
除了我和爸爸妈妈
staying with us.
还有一个叔叔
One of the 3 new credentials
那三本新证件里面
has the name of Xiang Yuansheng on it.
有一本名字叫向远生
It should have belonged to the man.
应该是给那个叔叔的
To become a policeman
远生哥哥为了当警察
to find the murderer,
替我找凶手
Yuansheng
就借用了
borrowed the name.
向远生这个名字
And his real name is Hua Zhen.
他本来的名字叫华桢
Hua Zhen?
华桢
So has he come to Shanghai
那他是从南京
from Nanjing?
来上海的吗
How
石老师
do you know that?
你怎么知道